In previous videos we were adding data to Git.
Now, lets have a look at how to get the older version of the files we need, without affecting the others.
Lets imagine that during the development process we've realized that we made a mistake in one of the files.
We would like to revert its version to the one of 2 commits ago.
We dont want to switch branches and everything, apart of this file should be kept as is, only get the older version of this file.
Surprisingly, we are already familiar with the command taht can make it, its "git checkout".
For example, lets restore the "index.html" file to the state of this commit.
For that let's call "git checkout" giving it the commit
can be as a link( this commit points to the master ) or an identifier, it doenst matter,
Можно ссылкой - на этот коммит указывает мастер - или идентификатором, это неважно.
then the path, which we want to restore, in our case its "index.html".
When specifying the path checkout works simpler, than it usually does.
It doesnt switch the branch, but gets the file specified
or it can also get several files and directories on the moment of commit specified.
You see? First of all, the file is updated, also note
the restored files were automatically added to the index by "checkout" command.
So now, if I run "git commit", then this, the older version of "index.html" will become current.
If we dont want it, we can, of course remove it from the index.
It can be done with "git reset index.html" command.
And, you see? Changes remained in the working directory, but were removed from the index.
The reset command can do a lot of things, we'll have a look at it later, but the way we used it, it reset the index for this particular file
Lets have a look at another example.
For example, we changed the file in the working directory, experimented a little,
but we dont like the changes and we would like to cancel them, without affecting the other files.
Same, lets run "git checkout". We need an older version of the files from the current commit, that is from "HEAD".
Done. "index.html" file is the same as we previously saved it in the repository.
Lets note that in this particular situation, lets revert the changes in the file
we could write it shorter, like that: "git checkout index.html", no need to specify the commit at all.
By that checkout will return the file to the working directory from the index.
In this case we didnt index the changes, so the version of the file in the index matches with the version in the HEAD.
Therefore the result will be same as above.
Executing and changes were reset.
Of course, the behavior is different if we have some of the changes indexed.
Then they would have been returned to the working directory.
So, checkout with path and commit reverts the file from that commit to the working directory and the index.
But checkout with path only reverts it from the index to the working directory.
There's one more trick about specifying the paths, which is quite typical for many git commands.
There can be a case when our project has a file or a directory with the same name as the commit or the branch.
For example, our project can have a directory named "master".
But when we call "git checkout master", how can checkout understand what do we mean: is master a path or a branch?
The logic is very simple here: checkout is trying to find the link or the commit with this identifier.
And if there's none, it assumes that its a path.
In our case, as master actually exists, this command will switch to the branch master.
But what if we want it to be a patch?
For that we have to specify a double dash "--".
This way allows us to avoid the ambiguity. Everything that goes after the "--" is treated as path.
If we need to use some flags or arguements, like commit, they are going before the double dash.
Once again: most of the time you dont need a double dash.
Like in the case with "index.html" above. Its obvious that we dont have a branch named "index.html".
Double dash is only needed for the case where we need to dissolve the ambiguity
Gladly we mostly dont need this in practice.